Finding aid for the June L. Mazer Lesbian Archive Collection of Audio Materials, 1970-1999 LSC.2230
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Autobiography - In the Best Interest, 1976-1986; Series 6.; 49 audio cassette tapes
  - #20 Auto/Bio Tape 1 of 1 May Sarton Interview, 27 April 1983; audio cassette tape (Box 5, Folder 3, Item 12)
  - Jean Cordova on lesbian movement 1970-80 (SCWU, SIP), August 1986; audio cassette tape (Box 5, Folder 3, Item 13)
- Talks Cassettes, 1979-1993; Series 7.; 48 audio cassette tapes
  - Pat Humphries - Demo, 29 March 1989; audio cassette tape (Box 5, Folder 4, Item 1)
    Includes songs: "Walls and Windows" "Ten Little Warheads" "Common Thread" "Never Turning Back"
  - "The First Spark" Rev. Mary Shelton, Church of Religious Science, 5 December 1993; audio cassette tape (Box 5, Folder 4, Item 2)
  - IMRU 9th Annual Gay Day 1986 Selections: Panel & Overwrought, audio cassette tape (Box 5, Folder 4, Item 3)
    Side 1 - Panel: Female Vocalists with Gay Male Cult Followings Side 2 - "Overwrought Productions" Does Dial Twisting Funny Stuff
  - Eloise on Gertrude Stein, undated; audio cassette tape (Box 5, Folder 4, Item 4)
  - Reinvoking the Grove Dina Metzger, undated; audio cassette tape (Box 5, Folder 4, Item 5)
  - Paula Gunn Allen, undated; audio cassette tape (Box 5, Folder 4, Item 6)
  - Lesbian Connectionist Spirituality by B. Love, 3 June 1990; audio cassette tape (Box 5, Folder 4, Item 7)
  - The Incomparable Hildegarde "On the Air" 1936-1944, 1981; audio cassette tape (Box 5, Folder 4, Item 8)
    16 songs performed by American cabaret singer Hildegard.
  - Jinx Beers at JMLC, 7 January 1990; audio cassette tape (Box 5, Folder 4, Item 9)
  - Lesbian Odyssey Narration, undated; audio cassette tape (Box 5, Folder 4, Item 10)
    Narrative for "Welcome"
  - Battering in Relationships Del Martin, undated; audio cassette tape (Box 5, Folder 4, Item 11)
    Radio Show Side 1 - Initial victim interview, Ranalee and Del Martin discussion Side 2 - Phone calls
  - KPFK - IMRU, 8 July 1984; audio cassette tape (Box 5, Folder 4, Item 12)
    Recording of the IMRU radio show on KPFK. Includes: Update portion of "time line," all of "I love to laugh," Kathy Hamilton discussion, part of Morris Kight
  - Women in the Arts, UWEX Robin Morgan, 1985; audio cassette tape (Box 5, Folder 4, Item 13)
  - Open Mike II, 21 January 1990; audio cassette tape (Box 5, Folder 4, Item 14-15)
    Tape is blank.
  - Alfredo / Two Old Women / The Disguise Sarah Greene, 1988; audio cassette tape (Box 5, Folder 4, Item 16)
  - Everyday Witch Tales Joyce Wexler-Ballard, undated; audio cassette tape (Box 5, Folder 4, Item 17)
  - Connexicus Susan Schreiber Sharon Siegel, 1985; audio cassette tape (Box 5, Folder 4, Item 18)
  - Coming Out Stories, 1983; audio cassette tape (Box 5, Folder 4, Item 19)
    Coming out stories told by women in Pamela Gray's Lesbian Lives class, SF State, Spring 1983. Guest lecturers Patty and Moonwise discussing disability.
  - Joan Nestle at UCLA, 19 January 1989; audio cassette tape (Box 5, Folder 5, Item 1)
    Joan Nestle, co-founder of the Lesbian Herstory Archives, reads and speaks at A Different Light Book Store.
  - Jinx Beers at JMLC post LN, undated; audio cassette tape (Box 5, Folder 5, Item 2)
  - Paula Gunn Allen, 23 April 1983; audio cassette tape (Box 5, Folder 5, Item 3)
  - Paula Gunn Allen, 31 January 1982; audio cassette tape (Box 5, Folder 5, Item 4)
  - Marilyn Murphy at JMLC, July 1990; audio cassette tape (Box 5, Folder 5, Item 5)
  - Lesbians, CEBV, AIDS & Safe Sex JoAnn Loulan, March 1987; audio cassette tape (Box 5, Folder 5, Item 6)
    Part of the Lesbian Sexuality Series. Tape description: "Recorded in March 1987, this tape provides information on what currently constitutes "safe sex" for lesbians, how AIDS is transmitted, who is at risk, and other relevant issues. JoAnn also discusses Chronic Epstein-Barr Virus (CEBV)."
  - "Red, White & Blues," and "Mean Mothers", undated; audio cassette tape (Box 5, Folder 5, Item 7)
    Side 1 - "Red White & Blues," Women Sing America Side 2 - "Mean Mothers," 16 Historic Blues Singers From Rosetta Records
  - The Carlin Case (Pacifica Radio), 1986; audio cassette tape (Box 5, Folder 5, Item 8)
  - Chrystos Reading at JMLC, undated; audio cassette tape (Box 5, Folder 5, Item 9)
  - Karla Jay - Sojourner Interview, 26 June 1979; audio cassette tape (Box 5, Folder 5, Item 10)
  - Washington Sisters, undated; audio cassette tape (Box 5, Folder 5, Item 11)
    Musical Demo Tape.
  - Old Lesbians 60+, undated; audio cassette tape (Box 5, Folder 5, Item 12)
    Interviews with lesbians over the age of 60. Produced by B. Love.
  - Sephardic Presentation Old Wives Tale, 18 February 1982; audio cassette tape (Box 5, Folder 5, Item 13)
  - "Gay Spirits: A Slightly Different Christmas Carol" / Snow Angel by Cris Williamson KPFK Radio, 25 December 1990; audio cassette tape (Box 5, Folder 5, Item 14)
    LGBT Christmas programming recorded from KPFK Radio.
  - "Why are Dykes Going Straight?", 24 October 1982; audio cassette tape (Box 5, Folder 5, Item 15)
  - "Just Kidding" Robin Tyler, 1985; audio cassette tape (Box 5, Folder 5, Item 16)
    Stand up comedy by Robin Tyler
  - Jamie Anderson, 1989; audio cassette tape (Box 5, Folder 5, Item 17)
    Includes songs: "Save Me All Your Sundays" "Wedding Song" "Straight Girl Blues" "Dark Chocolate" From the album "Closer to Home" on Tsunami Records
  - Interviews by Michael Jackson, 1986; audio cassette tape (Box 5, Folder 6, Item 1)
    Side 1: Ginny Foat interview by Michael Jackson, 10/4/1986 Side 2: Tommy Williams "More Than...etc," Malcolm Boyd with Michael Jackson, 2/4/1986
  - KPFK at L6 Day, 7 July 1991; audio cassette tape (Box 5, Folder 6, Item 2)
  - What is Ecofeminism?, undated; audio cassette tape (Box 5, Folder 6, Item 3)
  - Weaving the World Together, undated; audio cassette tape (Box 5, Folder 6, Item 4)
    by Riane Eisler
  - Lesbian Couples, 1989; audio cassette tape (Box 5, Folder 6, Item 5)
    "Counselors Clunis and Green talk about the pleasures and challenges of being part of a lesbian couple, from intimacy and sex to resolving conflict. Beginning with issues of definition, the authors chart the stages most couples go through--romance, conflict, commitment, collaboration--and offer affirming and wise advice on understanding and strengthening lesbian partnerships."
  - The Seven Words... George Carlin, 1986; audio cassette tape (Box 5, Folder 6, Item 6)
    Recording of George Carlin's stand up routine about the Seven Words you can't say on television, aired on Pacifica Radio.
  - In the House of the Riddle Mother 2 Clarissa Pinkola Estes, 1991; audio cassette tape (Box 5, Folder 6, Item 7)
    Lecture about common archetypal motifs in women's dreams.
  - Paula Gunn Allen reading at JMLC, 13 January 1991; audio cassette tape (Box 5, Folder 6, Item 8)
  - Linda Steed interviews 8- & 13-year-old girls, undated; audio cassette tape (Box 5, Folder 6, Item 9)
  - Our Lesbian Roots, Part 3: "Stein Colette, Sarton, Foster", 1980; audio cassette tape (Box 5, Folder 6, Item 10)
    Part 3 of a lecture series by Valerie Taylor.
    Duplicate tape: Box 2, Folder 17 of Autobiography - In the Best Interest
  - Our Lesbian Roots, Part 6: "The Young Ones Come on Strong", 1980; audio cassette tape (Box 5, Folder 6, Item 11)
    Part of a lecture series by Valerie Taylor
    Duplicate tape: Box 3, Folder 2 of Autobiography - In the Best Interest
  - Our Lesbian Roots, Part 7: "Non-Fiction", 1980; audio cassette tape (Box 5, Folder 6, Item 12)
    Part of a lecture series by Valerie Taylor.
    Duplicate tape: Box 3, Folder 3 of Autobiography - In the Best Interest
- Spoken Word Her/History Audio Cassettes, 1976-1987; Series 9.; 15 audio cassette tapes
  Recordings of various talks, interviews, oral histories, festivals, meetings. Topics ranging from lesbian activism, herstory, coming out, lesbian literature and poetry, music, and ageism.
  - JR Roberts Chicago Oral Herstory, 21 May 1978; audio cassette tape (Box 6, Folder 1, Item 1)
    Oral history with JR Roberts, discuss Roberts' involvement in lesbian community and activism in Chicago, including her personal experience and her work with the Women's Center.
  - Relics, 8 April 1980; audio cassette tape (Box 6, Folder 1, Item 2)
    60 minute recording of Herstory/women's group meeting in San Francisco, CA. Discuss building an archive, future meeting locations, future meeting agendas and protocol, upcoming events, including Gay and Lesbian Pride week and parade.
  - Women on Wheels, Santa Cruz, CA, February 1976; audio cassette tape (Box 6, Folder 1, Item 3)
    60 minute recording. Side one is recording of Women on Wheels concert performance in Santa Cruz, CA. Side two is an interview with an unnamed woman on the topic of monogamy, a heterosexual relationship she was in, and her experience of coming out as lesbian.
  - Florence Jaffee Oral History, 7 February 1981; audio cassette tape (Box 6, Folder 1, Item 4-6)
    60 minute recording oral history of Florence Jaffee. Interview by Lynn Fonfa of the West Coast Lesbian Collection. Discussed is her process of coming out, relationships and their effect on her emotional well-being, her experience living in San Francisco, and her work with the Daughter of Bilitis.
  - In the Life Tape, 17 August 1981; audio cassette tape (Box 6, Folder 1, Item 7-8)
    Group of women examine and talk about paper materials, discuss creation of t-shirts, and plan future events and programming at the Women's Center.
  - Older Women's Group at Berkeley Women's Center, undated; audio cassette tape (Box 6, Folder 1, Item 9)
    Tape is recording of Cris Williamson songs.
    Side A only. Audio quality is poor. Cassette ribbon is damaged.
  - Kinflicks Tape, 1987; audio cassette tape (Box 6, Folder 1, Item 10-11)
    Author: Lisa Alther Read by: Jo Beth Williams Novel, in audio format, with the protagonist, Virginia "Ginny" Hull Babcock Bliss. Begins with Ginny catching a plane to look after her ill mother. Recounts her childhood, teenage years, college years, and marriage. Blend of first-person and third-person narration. 90 minutes.
  - #1 Musical Performances by Beverly Shaw and Francis Faye, undated; audio cassette tape (Box 6, Folder 1, Item 12)
    Side one is musical recording of singer Beverly Shaw, "Tailored to Taste." Side two is musical recording of singer Francis Faye, "Caught in the Act." Both were nightclub singers in the 1940s and 1950s.
    Side one becomes unplayable after 6 minutes. Side two becomes unplayable after 2 minutes.
  - Interview with Nancy Manahan and Peg Cruikshank in Napa, 9 December 1984; audio cassette tape (Box 6, Folder 1, Item 13)
    60 minute oral history recording of Nancy Manahan and Peg Cruikshank. Interview by Cathy Zinsli. Interview takes place in Napa, California. Discuss discrimination and oppression against lesbians, how to respond to homophobia, and reasons why women remain in the closet.
  - First meeting of the West Coast Lesbian Collections archives, 27 March 1980; audio cassette tape (Box 6, Folder 1, Item 14)
    Group of women discussing development of lesbian archives, including goals for the archives and administrative issues. Lynn Fonfa and Cherrie Cox are on the recording.
  - Aging Lesbians: Research, undated; audio cassette tape (Box 6, Folder 1, Item 15)
    90 minute recording of talk with speakers presenting research findings on the topic of aging lesbians.
- LA Community Chorus, Menstruation/Menopause Cassettes, 1972-1986; Series 10.; 14 audio cassette tapes
  Audio recordings of LA Women's Community Chorus songs and meetings, with women discussing menopause, estrogen therapy, hormone therapy, menstruation, and other medical issues.
  - Menopause Tape, 17 March 1972; audio cassette tape (Box 6, Folder 2, Item 1-2)
    Discussion about personal experiences with menopause, estrogen therapy, hormone therapy, menstruation, miscarriages, physical and emotional side effects, and other medical issues.
  - Mary Nunn Tape, undated; audio cassette tape (Box 6, Folder 2, Item 3-4)
    Oral history interview with Mary Nunn discusses background, education, work experience, romantic relationships, sexuality,and personal experience with menstruation and menopause.
    Recording cuts out frequently.
  - Menstruation, 17 March 1972; audio cassette tape (Box 6, Folder 2, Item 5)
    90 minute recording of meeting, with women discussing personal experiences with menstruation, menopause, birth control pills, estrogen, pregnancy, child birth, and women's general health issues.
  - Lee's Men's Group Menstruation and Menopause, 1 March 1972; audio cassette tape (Box 6, Folder 2, Item 6)
    60 minute recording of Lee's Men's Group meeting and women's meeting. Side 1 is men's group. Discuss the experience women go through in a male dominated world. Begins with exercise that has men in group imagine what it would be like to menstruate as women do. Side 2 continues with women's group discussing personal experiences with menstruation and menopause.
  - Men's Group Menstruation and Menopause // Dorothy Matson, 1 March 1972; audio cassette tape (Box 6, Folder 2, Item 7)
    60 minute recording. Side 1 is men's group meeting and they discuss the women's movement and practice feeling and feeling what it would be like to be a woman, with the same physical experiences of menstruation and menopause. Side 2 is an interview with Dorothy Matson discussing her personal experience with sexuality, menopause, and women's health issues.
    Short periods of silence and very quiet talking on side 1.
  - Games and Simulation Paper Presentation, undated; audio cassette tape (Box 6, Folder 2, Item 8)
    15 minute recording of presentation of paper on the topic of games and simulation research.
    Audio on side 1 only.
  - The Los Angeles Women's Community Chorus 10th Anniversary Album, 1986; audio cassette tape (Box 6, Folder 2, Item 9-10)
    Recorded musical album in original packaging. Album liner notes, "This album was recorded at St. Augustine-by-the-Sea Episcopal Church, Santa Monica, California, Summer, 1986. Recording on location: Digital Brothers Newport Beach, California, Overdubs and Mixdowns: Frank Sullivan Studio, Pasadena, California. Side 1 song titles: Woman Spirit/Woman Strong, New Woman Rising, On Children, Aure Volante, Arms Open in the Night. Side 2 song titles: The Fury, La Andina, Days of Theocracy, Working Women's Medley
    6 duplicates
- Poetry Cassettes, 1980s; Series 14.; 13 audio cassette tapes
  Recordings of poetry readings, poetry performances, radio shows, and professionally-recorded poetry. Authors included are Kitty Tsui, Willyce Kim, Eloise Klein Healy, Pat Parker, Uncle Ruthie, Elana Dykewomon, B Love, May Sarton, Virginia Roth, Terry Wolverton, and others.
  - Dyke Proud, 18 June 1988; audio cassette tape (Box 6, Folder 3, Item 1)
    Complete title is Dyke Proud: A Lesbian Poetry Reading from the 3rd International Feminist Book Fair, Montreal 1988. The recording includes the poets: Elana Dikewomon, Judith Barrington, Libby Namjoshi, Gilliam Hanscombe, Judy Grahn, Gloria Anzaldua, Daphne Marlatt, and Betsy Warland.
  - World of Light: A Portrait of May Sarton, 1982; audio cassette tape (Box 6, Folder 3, Item 2)
    Side 1 is "World of Light," Sarton's book of portraits of significant persons from her life. Her subjects include her father, the noted science historian George Sarton; people in the arts-Elizabeth Bowen, Louise Brogan, Jean Dominique; and people who lived lives remote from the center-Marc, the vigneron of Satigny, in the foothills of the Jura mountains, and Quig, the painter of Nelson, New Hampshire. Side 2 is a recording of Sarton reading additional poems and her personal commentary. May Sarton is the pen name of Eleanore Marie Sarton an American poet, novelist, and memoirist. She lived from 1912 to 1995.
  - Pat Parker: Movement in Black, 30 March 1989; audio cassette tape (Box 6, Folder 3, Item 3)
    Recording of a poetry reading by Pat Parker at California State University Los Angeles on 3/30/1989. Parker was an African American lesbian feminist poet. Born in Houston, Texas in 1944 and passed away from breast cancer in 1989.
  - Eloise Klein Healy: Some From Ten 1975-1985, audio cassette tape (Box 6, Folder 3, Item 4)
  - 1st 50 Feet, ca. 1980s; audio cassette tape (Box 6, Folder 3, Item 5)
    Poem by Uncle Ruthie, or Ruthie Buell. Uncle Ruthie is a poet, children's musician, artist, and teacher.
    Recording of one poem only.
  - Joint Poetry Reading: IGLA & Mazer, 6 May 1990; audio cassette tape (Box 6, Folder 3, Item 6)
    Recording of the Joint Poetry Reading organized by the International Gay and Lesbian Association and the June L. Mazer Lesbian Archives.
  - KPFK: The Poetry Connection, 21 December 1991; audio cassette tape (Box 6, Folder 3, Item 7)
    Recording of Los Angeles news radio KPFK 90.7 FM show, The Poetry Connection, with hosts: Wanada Coleman and Austin Strauss. Guest writer is Eloise Klein Healy and she reads from her book of poetry, "Artemis in Echo Park." The hosts also engage in discussion and questioning about Healy's work. Healy is an American poet who has published 5 books of poetry and founded Arktoi Books. Austin Strauss and Wanda Coleman, news radio show
  - Stanford Women's Poetry Conference: Kitty Tsui Reading, 17 April 1982; audio cassette tape (Box 6, Folder 3, Item 8)
    Recording of poetry performance at the Stanford Women's Poetry Conference. Kitty Tsui reads her work. Although born in Hong Kong in 1952, Kitty Tsui spent her childhood in California. She earned a degree in Creative writing from San Francisco State University. Her poetry and prose has been published in over 35 anthologies, and she has published three books. Tsui is also an artist and competitive body-builder.
  - Sapphic Journeys: Sensuous Poetry for Lesbians, 1980; audio cassette tape (Box 6, Folder 3, Item 9)
    Professional recording of poetry and music. Sappho was a female poet philosopher who lived around 630 B.C. She wrote sensual, erotic poetry about women and goddesses. The recording was produced by Margo Strik and directed by Ginger Roth. Poems read by Etoile Monet and Dimitra Stukas. Contributing authors: Sappho, Loretta Lotman, Terry Wolverton, Aslan Heidorn, Carol Quinn, Gail Browne, Celeste [Sky] Crane, Roberta McDaniel, Dee Bruseke, Virginia Roth, and Doris Davenport. Copyright 1980 by Womonsounds.
  - Elana Dikewomon Poetry Performance, 9 May 1981; audio cassette tape (Box 6, Folder 3, Item 10)
    Recording of poetry performance with Elana Dykewomon. Born Elana Nachman, Dykewomon was born in 1949 and is a Jewish lesbian activist, award-winning author, editor and teacher. She has published articles, novels, anthologies, and books of poetry.
  - Poetry Performance: Kitty Tsui & Willyce Kim, 5 November 1981; audio cassette tape (Box 6, Folder 3, Item 11-12)
    Recording of poetry performance, featuring Willyce Kim and Kitty Tsui. Kim was born in Honolulu, Hawaii in 1946, worked for the Women's Press Collective in Oakland, CA, and has written two books of poetry and two novels. In this recording, Kim reads from her novel, "Dancer Dawkins and the California Kid." Kitty Tsui is a Chinese-American lesbian. Raised in California, Tsui is a writer, artist, activist, and body-builder. She has authored three books and has been published in 35 anthologies. Tsui's performance is accompanied by music.
  - Lesbian Incest Survivors, 1 March 1990; audio cassette tape (Box 6, Folder 3, Item 13)
    Produced by B Love. Personal narratives shared by women, describing accounts of sexual molestation and abuse within family and close friend relationships.
- Liz Maines Gay Radio Show KFCF 88.1, 1994; Series 18.; 17 audio cassette tapes
  Collection of audio recordings consisting largely of episodes of It's A Queer Thang, a monthly radio show featuring news, music and entertainment from the local and LGBT community. The radio show started in 1991 on KFCF 88.1 FM in Fresno and continues to air, with hosts Liz Maines, Jeff Robinson, and Tom Brandenberry.
  - It's A Queer Thang: Mazer Collection, April 1996; audio cassette tape (Box 6, Folder 4, Item 1)
    Recording of the Liz Maines Gay Radio Show, It's A Queer Thang, on KCFC 88.1 from Fresno, California. The topic of this episode is the June L. Mazer Lesbian Archives and its collections. The discussion includes the Mazer's history, notable materials, fundraisers, and plans for the future.
  - It's A Queer Thang: LGBT People of Color, March 1994; audio cassette tape (Box 6, Folder 4, Item 2-3)
    Recording of the Liz Maines Gay Radio Show, It's A Queer Thang, on KCFC 88.1 from Fresno, California. This episode features an interview with the group, People of Color. The group supports bi-sexual, gay, lesbian, and trans-sexual ethnic minorities through support group meetings, social meetings, cultural activities, and political events. Liz Maines is out, Jeff Robinson and Tom Brandenberry fill in for her.
  - KPFA Coverage of March on Washington, 25 April 1993; audio cassette tape (Box 6, Folder 4, Item 4-7)
    KPFA coverage of The March on Washington for Lesbian, Gay, and Bi Equal Rights and Liberation that took place in Washington, D.C. on April 25, 1993. The March on Washington was a large political rally with a focus on lesbian, gay, bisexual, and transgender civil rights that included a march, rallies, exhibits and candlelight vigils.
  - It's A Queer Thang: San Francisco Gay Men's Chorus, May 1994; audio cassette tape (Box 6, Folder 4, Item 8-9)
    Hosts Jeff Robinson and Tom Brandenberry interview Sam Hill, Paul Taylor, and Paul Fisher from the San Francisco Gay Men's Chorus. They discuss the Chorus' history, purpose, outreach, and upcoming events.
  - It's A Queer Thang: Lesbian Parenting, 1994; audio cassette tape (Box 6, Folder 4, Item 10)
    Hosts Jeff Robinson and Tom Brandenberry interview Leah Maxwell and Mandy Diotenzo, lesbian parents whose children were removed from their home in Fresno County, California. Child Protective Services took the children away from the couple based on allegations of abuse, however the women suspect it is solely an issue of discrimination.
  - It's A Queer Thang: Peace Corps, February 1994; audio cassette tape (Box 6, Folder 4, Item 11)
    Hosts Liz Maines, Jeff Robinson, and Tom Brandenberry interview Christopher Han, a gay peace corps member. They discuss his background, reasons for joining the peace corps, the work he does in Western Samoa with the peace corps, and his experience as a gay man in that area of the world.
  - It's A Queer Thang: Gay Lesbian Business Association, [ca. 1990s]; audio cassette tape (Box 6, Folder 4, Item 12-13)
    Hosts Liz Maines and Jeff Robinson interview Ken from the Central California Alliance. The business association's purpose is to allow gays, lesbians, and heterosexuals to come together to network and socialize in business. They discuss reasons for its formation, its purpose, and goals.
    Tape 2 is a duplicate
  - It's A Queer Thang: AIDS Team Study, [ca. 1990s]; audio cassette tape (Box 6, Folder 4, Item 14)
    Hosts Liz Maines and Jeff Robinson interview Russ Decker, from the Central Valley AIDS Team. The organization conducted and released results of a survey on the attitudes, knowledge and behaviors regarding AIDS of gay and bisexual men in the Fresno area.
  - It's A Queer Thang: Ken Frees GL Film Festival, [ca. 1990s]; audio cassette tape (Box 6, Folder 4, Item 15)